好的，所以我们要去验证，
All right, so we're gonna go to validation,
我们要快速制作一个验证库。
we're gonna make a validation library right quick.
[笑] 所以我只是用所有这些幺半群来打击你。
[LAUGH] So I just kind of pummeled you with all these monoids.
但是你可以看到它是如何暗示建筑的，对吧？
But you can see how it hints at architecture, right?
我们可以开始说，
We're able to start to say like,
我们的应用程序类型是一个异步错误处理的东西，或者是一个类似报告的东西。
our type of app is an async error handling thing or it's a report like thing.
在这种情况下，我们将围绕验证进行架构。
And in this case, we're gonna do architecture around validation.
所以我们会说验证是一种组合。
So we're gonna say validations are a thing that combined.
从根本上说，如果我有一个验证和
Fundamentally, if I have a validation and
比方说，isPresent 和我做那个检查和
let's say, isPresent and I do that check and
我想将它与另一个像 isEmail 连接起来。
I wanna concat that with another one like isEmail.
我们拿一些对象，我们会说 object.name 和 object.email。
We take some objects and we'll take say object.name and object.email.
我应该得到的是，组合错误或
What I should get is, either the combined errors or
原来的对象，对，选择。
the original object, right, the choice.
所以，我们想建立一些结合了一堆验证和礼物的东西
So, we wanna build something that combines a bunch of validations and presents
我带着他们所有的错误或一个成功的对象通过了挑战。
me with all their errors or a successful object that got through the gauntlet.
所以让我们尝试构建这个，
So let's try to build this,
我要慢慢来，问问题。
and I'm going to go slow, ask questions.
但是，我们已经开始了，我们想要结束什么？
But, we're already gonna kind of start with, what do we want to end up with?
我认为一个不错的 API 就是这个。
And I think a nice API would be this.
我们会说验证就是我们有名字的东西
We'll say validations is this thing where we have name
isPresent、电子邮件、isEmail 等。
isPresent, an email, isEmail, and so on.
所以我们会说我们会更进一步。
So we'll say like we'll take it further.
我们可以说，好吧，我想用 isPresent 连接它，对吧？
We could say, well, I wanna concat that with also isPresent, right?
我们会在结束之前做到这一点。
We'll do that before the end.
但我们的想法是我们提供一个对象键值，我希望验证
But the idea is that we provide an object key value and I want the validation to
对应于密钥，我希望能够组合和编写验证。
correspond to the key and I wanna be able to combine and compose validations.
每个人都了解问题的框架吗，我们正在努力做什么？
Is everybody understand the framing of the problem, what we are trying to do?
对此有任何疑问，是吗？
Any questions on that, yep?
&gt;&gt; 这个，如果我们把它换成不同的语言，
&gt;&gt; This, if we were to take it into different language,
只是不同类型的对象，对吗？
would just be a different type of objects, right?
&gt;&gt; 是的，没错。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, exactly.
&gt;&gt; 好的。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; 它可以只是命名为巴黎，我只是想能够提供，
&gt;&gt; It could just be named Paris, I just wanna be able to provide,
这是我想要运行此验证的属性。
this is the attribute I wanna run this validation on.
我们想做一些事情，比如验证验证。
And we wanna do something maybe like validate validations.
[笑] 然后我们会给它一些对象
[LAUGH] And then we'll give it some object and
我们希望得到我们的对象或一堆错误。
we hope to get our object back or a bunch of errors.
好的，让我们继续编写 isPresent。
All right, so let's go ahead and write isPresent.
而且，实际上你知道什么，没关系。
And, actually you know what, nevermind.
在我们做任何其他事情之前，让我们先写这个验证。
Let's go ahead and write this validate first before we do anything else.
我喜欢从颜色开始，对吧？
I like to start at the color, right?
所以我要创造，所以我们已经有了这个东西。
So I'm gonna create, so we already have this thing.
现在让我们简化它，我们稍后再做。
Let's simplify it for now and we'll do this later.
但我们说，事实上，让我们从两者的 isPresent 开始。
But we say, in fact, let's just start with isPresent on both.
所以我们有一个非常简单的用例，我们将从调用代码开始
So we have a very simple use case, we're gonna start with the calling code and
我们的工作方式备份。
kind of work our way back up.
所以我们的对象有一个名字。
So we have our object that has a name.
还有，布赖恩和一封电子邮件，以及
And, brian and an email, and
那将是 brian@brian.com。
that would be brian@brian.com.
好的，太好了。
All right, great.
我们将验证这一点。
And we'll validate that.
所以这将是我们的回应，我们会继续
So it will be our response and we'll go ahead and
console.log 无论响应是什么。
console.log whatever that response is.
好的，太好了。
All right, great.
所以我们必须去写验证，所以让我们这样做。
So we have to go write validate, so let's do that.
验证是键值的规范，对吗？
And validations is the specification of key values, right?
所以这就像我们的规范对象，我想，我不知道。
So that'll be like our spec object, I guess, I don't know.
我的名字很糟糕，只是称为我们的规范。
I'm terrible at names, just called our spec.
[笑] 然后我们有一个对象。
[LAUGH] And then we have an object.
我们称之为记录或其他什么。
We call it a record or whatever.
然后我们想做的是在规范上说 object.keys。
And then what we wanna do is say object.keys on the spec.
所以对于这些名字中的每一个，好吧，如果我们 foldMap 会怎样，对吗？
So for each of these names, well, what if we foldMap that, right?
我们将把所有东西都组合起来，所以从一个列表和 foldMap 开始。
We're gonna be combining everything, so start that in a list and foldMap here.
我们相当肯定我们现在要 foldMap 这就是我这样做的原因。
We're fairly certain we're gonna foldMap right now is why I'm doing this.
所以带入清单。
So bring in list.
List=require immutable-ext。
List=require immutable-ext.
我们将它们折叠成什么？
And what are we folding mapping them into?
好吧，我们为什么不从一个开始，对吧，
Well, why don't we start with an either, right,
任何一种都已经为我们做到了这一点。
either kind of already does this for us.
我们不必写任何东西。
We don't have to write anything.
所以让我们从我们的类型中引入。
So let's go bring in either from our types.
我很喜欢这种行为，
I do love this behavior,
它就像告诉我我在文件夹结构中的确切位置。
it's like tells me exactly where I am in the folder structure.
这是值得的痛苦。
It's worth the pain.
所以，好吧，所以
So, okay, so
我们有一个要么，我们将从要么中拉出右边的左边。
we have an either and we'll pull out the left in the right from the either.
所以我们可以随意使用它们。
So we have those at our disposal.
太好了，所以我们要做的就是说我们从任意一个开始作为我们的空。
Great, so we're gonna do is say we're start with either of right as our empty.
然后我们将从任何一个对象开始作为我们的初始
And then we'll start with either of the object as our initial
初始对象，对，然后我们的初始为空。
initial object, right, and then our initial empty.
因为我们想要么返回对象的权利，要么
Because we wanna either return the right of the object or
剩下一堆错误，然后我们将接收每个键。
a left of a bunch of errors, and then we're gonna take in each key.
让我们稍微扩展一下，去掉卷发，
Let's just kind of expand this out for a second, get rid of the curlies,
别担心。
don't worry.
[笑] 然后我们在这里要做的是说，所以如果我们调用规范键，
[LAUGH] And then what we'll do here is say, so if we call the spec key,
这将从那个对象中取出这个东西，对吧？
that will get this thing out of that object, right?
规范键是名称，我可以得到作为验证的值。
The spec keys are the names and I can get the value which is the validation out.
我们将对对象键运行验证，对吗？
And we'll run the validation on the object key, right?
很酷，这应该会回报我们。
Cool, and that should return us.
我们可以这样说，好吧，如果这是真的，
We could say something like, well, if it's true,
我们会返回一个 Right 这个值，对吧？
we'll return a Right of this value, right?
所以这个对象的权利，每个人都很好，它奏效了。
So right of the object, everybody's good, it worked.
否则，我们会给你一个左边的嘿嘿，让我们只是为了
Otherwise, we'll return you a left of hey, let's just for
屏幕的缘故，我们会说关键，男孩，关键坏了。
the screen sake, we'll say key, boy, key bad.
[笑] 来了。
[LAUGH] Here we go.
我们要从那个开始，看看它在哪里结束。
We're gonna start with that, see where it ends up.
好吧，我要摆脱这些。
Okay, I'm gonna get rid of these.
所以现在我们要返回一个要么你要么可以猫所以事情很好。
So now we're returning an either and you either can cats so things are good.
我会写 isPresent，我们会说，我不知道它需要一个 x 和
And I'll write isPresent, we'll say, I don't know it takes an x and
它只是不是 X 射线。
it's just not X-ray.
很酷，生活很美好。
Cool, life is good.
让我们看看发生了什么。
Let's see what happens.
如果我运行这个，节点库验证，
If I run this, node lib validations,
当然我已经在lib中了。
of course I'm already in lib.
为什么我要离开 lib 然后回来？
Why would I leave lib and come back?
已经到了。
It's already right here.
好吧，酷。
All right, cool.
但是这里发生了什么？
But what happened here?
为什么是人？
Why is it man?
[声音] Concat 不是函数，
[SOUND] Concat is not a function,
权利必须持有必须连接的东西。
right must be holding something that must be concatenate.
那不是我们想要的。
That's not we want.
我们不想将对象与带有对象的对象连接起来，对吗？
We don't wanna concatenate objects with objects wiht objects, right?
所以我们在这里要做出一些决定，我们实际上可以
So we have a few decisions here to make, we can actually
首先使用另一个我没有提到的幺半群，[笑] 或作为一个半群。
use another monoid that I didn't mention called first, [LAUGH] or as a semigroup.
因为我们不能做那个幺半群。
Because we can't make that monoid.
但是我们可以说，我们将首先使用这个对象，
But we could say, we'll use this object first,
那总是只需要第一个。
that always just takes the first one.
然后是我的工作。
And then my work.
我可以继续做到这一点，所以它总是保持第一件事。
I can go ahead and make that so it always keep the first thing.
但我会马上告诉你，这里发生的事情是 Left 只是
But I'll tell you right off the bat, what's happening here is Left is just
当它达到第一次验证时会短路。
gonna short circuit when it hits the first validation.
我们不希望那样。
And we don't want that.
我们希望它收集错误，对吗？
We want it to collect the errors, right?
即使我们在这里放了一个数组，而且
Even if we put an array here, And
我们实际上可以证明这一点，而不是使用 First，
we can actually demonstrate this instead of using First,
我只是把它放在数组中，因为一个数组连接。
I'll just put this in array because an array concats.
事实上，它被称为自由幺半群，因为你
In fact, it's called the free monoids because you
总是可以在那里拍东西。
can always slap something in there.
所以，它最终给了我们一个，如果我们停止这样做，就把它折叠起来。
So, it does end up giving us a either and if we stop doing this, just fold it out.
给它，我会写任何函数。
Give it, I'll write any functions.
我们会得到console.log，抱歉。
We would get the console.log, sorry.
所以我们在这里取得了很多成功。
So we get a bunch of successes here.
如果我删除一个，说名字不好。
If I remove one, say name bad.
[笑] 但如果我把这两个都去掉，我们就不会被命名为坏的
[LAUGH] But if I remove both, we won't get named bad and
电子邮件不好，我们只收到第一个，对吗？
email bad we just get the first one, right?
如果我收到另一个邮件，邮件就会变差。
And if I get the other one will get email bad.